[whoops]
[whooshes]
- [humming]
- [grunts]
[both grunting]
[laughs hysterically]
[intriguing music playing]
Well, kid, ready for our assignment?
[laughing gleefully]
Look, if you're gonna be a bounty hunter,
you'll have to sound more intimidating
than that.
[clears throat]
[laughs wickedly]
[sighs] Coruscant wasn't built in a day.
Let's go meet our contact.
[hums]
[whoops]
[Mando] Be careful in here.
We have powerful enemies.
Like those pirates we ran out of Nevarro.
So stay alert.
We don't want any--
- [all] Surprise!
- [Mando] Ahh!
[all screaming]
Suprise?
Peli!
What are you doing here?
I'm supposed to meet a contact
for an important assignment.
Your contact was Peli.
Hey Mando, I got a big time
bounty-huntin' job for you, see?
And bring that cute kid with you too, see?
Uh, hey, get out of the shot!
[clears throat]
And I ain't Peli Motto in disguise, see?
Wait. You?
Were Tough-o Guy-o?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
But it's all good because you came!
Now we can have this party
with all your friends.
And we can show you how much we appreciate
everything you've done for us.
We're leaving.
Mando, you are gonna have fun today
whether you have fun or not.
You Mandalorians all say,
"This is the way".
Well, for today,
this is the way, right, buddy?
[intriguing music playing]
[Mando sighs deeply]
- [all cheering]
- Let's party!
[upbeat music playing]
Mando, where did you get
all these friends?
I thought you kept to yourself?
Oh, he did.
Din Djarin here was the loneliest loner
who ever loned.
- Till that kid came along.
- [all exclaiming]
It's one heck of a tale!
I don't like to talk about myself.
Well, good thing I do!
Gather around, everyone.
I'll tell you the exciting story
of how a little green kid
turned a stone-cold bounty hunter
into a warm and fuzzy
stone-cold bounty hunter.
How could you tell our story?
You were only there for a tiny part of it.
I'm a mechanic at a spaceport.
Everybody tells me everything.
So, the way I hear it,
is it all went down like this.
Mando had just come back
from some bounty-hunting
with a ship
full of captured bad guys on ice.
This day, Mando got the assignment
that would change his life.
The Mandalorian, meet your new client.
He is called The Client.
- [sniffs]
- That's it? The Client?
Yes, we share the same first name, "The".
Dr. Pershing, and I desire for you
to go to Arvala-7
and acquire an asset for us.
This asset is called--
The Asset?
Your powers of perspicacity
are remarkable.
Now, I cannot divulge
the asset's identity to you,
nor tell you its height,
color or shape of its ears.
I can only say it is 50 years old,
which, by any measure, you and I go by,
is quite old.
Why did you say that so weird?
I did it... for reasons.
Here is your first payment.
Something Mandalorians greatly treasure,
Beskar steel.
When you deliver the asset to me,
there will be much more
from where that came from.
- [crashes]
- [screams]
[Peli] So Mando took the Beskar
to the last refuge of the Mandalorians
on Nevarro, the forge of The Armorer.
- [hissing]
- [clangs]
[Armorer] For you.
This is the Way.
Now I must go
and fulfill my bounty-hunting contract.
This is the Way.
Can you show me where the door is?
Wait. Are you saying this is the way out,
or just "This is the Way"?
- This is the Way.
- Ugh.
I'll find the exit on my own.
[Peli] To capture his bounty,
Mando went to Arvala-7.
It's a desolate planet, but way classier
than the other six Arvalas, oof!
There, he was aided
by a wise Ugnaught named Kuiil
who led him
to where The Asset was being held.
Ugh, pirates.
I command you to produce the asset.
And a competing bounty droid.
- [gun cocking]
- [gunfire]
Who's a showoff.
That-- That droid was doing the robot.
[grunting]
[grunts]
[Peli] Mando fought his way
to the fortress
and convinced that deadly droid
to work with him and split the reward.
We're surrounded,
but I think we can beat these guys.
[Droid] Negative. My manufacturer
protocols dictate I cannot be captured.
Initiating self-destruct sequencing.
Don't self-destruct!
- Are you nuts?
- [soldier grunts]
My sanity has been questioned.
- Initiating self-destruct sequencing.
- [alarm blaring]
Stop it, you crazy hunk of junk.
You have called me a nasty name.
- Initiating self--
- [grunts]
[Peli] Things went on like that for a bit.
[Droid] It might rain later,
initiating, so--
That's enough!
Uh-oh!
[explosion]
Let's get this 50-year-old asset.
[device beeping]
It's just a kid.
[Droid] I am programmed to terminate.
[gunshot]
No.
[thudding]
[Peli] Mando's tough shell
cracked a teensy bit that day,
but there was one little problem
in bringing the kid back to the client.
Well, actually,
a whole bunch of little problems.
[all whooping]
My ship! I just had it waxed.
[Peli] Kuiil talked to the Jawas, and he
got them to promise to fix Mando's ship
if he fought a beast called a mudhorn
and got one of its precious eggs.
[Mando grunts]
[grunting]
[Jawas whooping]
[coos]
Yeah, I like you, too,
but this is no time to be adorable.
[roars]
[swishing]
[mudhorn grunts]
[Mando] It's like he's moving that thing
with some kind of unseen force.
It is called the Force.
They have got to work
on better names for stuff.
[exhilarating instrumental music playing]
[mudhorn grunts]
[whooping triumphantly]
[laughs]
[Peli] With the kid's help,
Mando got the egg...
[speaking in foreign language]
...and his ship back.
[Mando] Ooh-Teeny.
[Peli] So Mando took the kid back
to the client to fulfill his assignment.
[both] Aww!
Cease that! We are Imperial Remnants.
We do not "aww"!
[both] Aww!
Stop it. Here is
your payment, Mandalorian.
Now you may take one last
wistful look at the adorable child
before we do terrible,
horrible, painful things to it.
[whimpers]
[somber instrumental music playing]
No!
[Peli] All of a sudden,
Mando had the X Empire after him.
The hunter was now the hunted,
and then the most exciting thing happened.
- They met me!
- [laughs]
[grunts]
[Peli] The end!
- [Jawas cheering]
- [giggles]
[Mando] Wait, wait, stop.
[grunts] A whole bunch
of other stuff happened.
Ugh. Fine.
You know I'm not getting paid for this.
[Peli] So Mando tangled
with the lethal Fennec Shand,
and then teamed up
with some nasty bad guys
to free another nasty bad guy
from a grody prison transport.
But the nasty bad guys were so nasty
that they double crossed Mando.
And so he ended up putting them all
in the prison ship,
which is where I got this mug.
[Jawas gasping]
Come on, Mando.
It's not how it looks.
We betrayed you for money!
[Peli] All the fighting and fleeing
was just exhausting.
- Oh, can you imagine?
- [honks]
So Mando was happy
when his old friend, Greef Karga,
called with an offer to return to Navarro
for a truce with the bounty hunters.
Mando, buddy, come on back.
I swear this is not a trick.
It was a trick!
He was just luring Mando
back to ambush him.
[all booing]
I said I'm sorry!
I made it up to Mando
and helped them escape.
Greef organized a plan to take out
the bad guys once and for all.
And Kuiil helped by making sure the kid
would be protected during the battle.
You, my sensors, detect awkwardness.
Do not fear, IG-11.
I have spoken.
This thing is a deadly threat.
Not anymore.
I have spoken again.
Now my primary function
is to protect the child.
He has been reprogrammed by me.
I have spoken again.
- Again.
- No way.
Once a killer, always a killer.
You do not trust my nurturing instincts.
Initiating self-destruct.
- Okay, okay, fine.
- [alarm blaring]
You can watch the kid.
Now let's go take out those Imperials.
[both gasping]
[grunts]
[all screaming]
[gasps]
I am also experiencing
terror of the pew pew pews!
They're gone. We win!
They're back. We lose!
[dramatic music playing]
[Peli] It was Moff Gideon, a super scary
former Imperial big cheese.
He was the one who wanted
the kid the whole time.
[all booing]
Hand over that 50-year-old child.
There's nowhere to run, Mandalorian.
This is the Way. Down!
- [all exclaiming]
- After them!
I need that child... for reasons!
[all scream]
[Peli] And they made a run for it
in the lava river under Nevarro.
Just a bit further, and we'll be safe.
Next up, Imperial Ambush station.
Ambush station?
Stormtroopers.
This is gonna be a tough fight.
[Droid] Negative.
I am programmed to protect the child.
To fulfill my function, I will engage
the enemy alone and self-destruct.
Thank you for your sacrifice.
Uh, aren't you going to stop me?
No, you're right.
- This is the only way to save the child.
- [squeals]
Me and my big
speech processing unit.
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
I am melting so slowly. Ow!
Ow! Ow!
Greetings, troopers,
please stand there doing nothing
while I activate this
- beeping thing in my chest.
- [alarm beeping]
[stormtroopers yelling]
[Peli] It looked like they were saved,
but, uh-uh!
[laughs wickedly]
Moff Gideon!
[gunfire]
[laughs wickedly]
You can't touch me in here, Mando!
- Uh-oh!
- [beeping]
I told the Empire to put
windshield wipers on these things.
[explosion]
Uh, do you think we should go make sure
Moff Gideon didn't somehow
survive that crash?
[both] Nah.
I will get that child yet.
- [phone beeping]
- [line ringing]
Mom, can you come pick me up?
That was a noble sacrifice
IG-11 made to save the child,
- blowing himself to pieces like that.
- I did what I had to do.
[exclaims]
How are you here?
You self-destructed!
I got better, then I got destroyed again.
Then I got better again.
It's sort of what I do.
- [distant explosion]
- [all exclaim]
What was that?
- Imperials!
- [gun cocking]
[guns cocking]
Wow, it stinks to be those guys.
Is this where the party's at?
- Migs?
- Mando!
- Happy birthday!
- It's not my birthday.
Oh, that's good.
I didn't get you anything.
Do you like my ride? I stole it
from a pirate junkyard on Jakku.
Wait. Why would you do anything nice
for Mando?
He put you in prison.
He's my buddy now.
He busted me out to help him rescue
the kid after the Imperials kidnapped him.
[stutters] Kidnapped?
Oh! It's a wicked great story.
And I was there for at least 20% of it.
So Mando wasn't alone anymore.
He had a kid, but now he had to bring him
to be with his own kind,
the powerful guardians of justice
in the galaxy, the Jethros.
- [all] Jedi!
- Right.
- Jedis.
- Jedi!
Okay, Jedi, get over yourself.
Yourselves!
All right?
So, anyway, Mando heard
there was another Mandalorian
and Mos Pelgo,
who could help him find some Jedi.
But when he got there, it wasn't
a Mandalorian, it was just a regular guy.
A rugged marshal named Cobb Salad.
Vanth. The name is Cobb Vanth.
Okay, fine!
- Cobb Vanth.
- Thank you.
He was wearing some other guy's armor.
Oh! You'll never guess whose armor it was.
It's a big name. Very famous.
So spoil it!
Mando believed the armor
should only be worn by a Mandalorian.
So the marshal proposed a deal.
I'll tell you what. You can have the armor
if you help me and my people
here with a problem.
[sighs in exasperation] Let me guess.
I have to fight a monster.
No, you don't have to fight a monster.
You have to fight a dragon.
[roaring]
- [whimpers]
- Here we go again.
I need you to loan me
a bantha strapped with explosives.
Well, you're in luck, because I always
keep a couple of those lying around.
[grunts]
[roaring]
- [bell dinging]
- Dragon, come to dinner!
[Mando] This is going to stink.
- [roaring]
- [gasps]
[belches]
[beeps]
[Migs] Mando saved the day.
And if he blew up two more monsters,
he'd get a free sandwich.
Try the roast womp rat on rye.
It's to die for.
[Migs] Mando left with the armor
and a lead on where to find some Jedi
to help the kid.
And you won't believe
all the crazy stuff that happened next.
This is the 80% part that I wasn't
there for, but here we go anyway.
First, he had to take this frog lady
to meet a frog husband.
But they had a crash landing.
And Mando had to fight off
another giant monster.
This time, a big spider.
The frog husband sent Mando
to meet this lady Mando named Bo-Katan.
They got in a crazy battle,
and then Bo-Katan told them...
I gotta get that dark saber thing
from Moff Bad Guy
and reclaim the throne of Mandalore.
Good luck with that, but I'm outie.
[Migs] So Mando and the kid went back
to Nevarro and fought off pirates.
[grunts]
[Migs] Then they found
the great Jedi, Ahsoka Tano.
And she was all like...
Pretty snazzy entrance, huh?
Ever see anybody spin
two of these light up dealies?
[Migs] Mando and Ahsoka teamed up
to defeat an evil tyrant
and free a whole town.
Ahsoka sent Mando to a planet where
the kid could reach out to the other Jedi.
But what they didn't know was
Moff Bad Guy put a tracking beacon
on Mando's ship.
- [chuckles]
- [alarm blaring]
So Moff Bad Guy
was on his way to take the kid
who Mando finally found out
his name!
He is called Goo-Goo.
Grogu. His name is Grogu.
At least I didn't call him Baby Yoda!
So Mando got the kid to the Jedi place
where he could connect to the Jedi
using that Jedi mind thing
that all the Jedi do.
Are you happy now that I got it right?
- [Mando] Is that a Jedi?
- [Migs] It wasn't a Jedi.
It was a mystery adversary.
Another bounty hunter, the very same one
whose armor Cob Vanth gave to Mando,
probably the most famous
bounty hunter of all!
- [whooping]
- Go ahead. You tell it. It
It was Boba Fett
and he was with Fennec Shand.
[Mando] Hey, that's my armor!
I fought off a big monster to get it.
I lost it in the stomach
of a bigger monster!
[Peli] Uh, guys.
guys, I have a better ship.
My ship is way better.
You can't even tell which part
is the front and which is the back.
That's what's so great about it.
Hey! Why don't you two stop
your ship measuring contest and look up!
They blew up my ship.
He left mine alone.
They know how great it is.
Enough about the ships!
The kid is in trouble.
[dramatic music playing]
Yoink!
Grogu!
[whistles]
How do you like me now, Mando?
I didn't like you before,
and now I like you even less.
That makes sense!
Bye.
[Migs] Mando was devastated.
He knew he had to save Grogu
from those evil imps.
But now he had a group
of friends to help him.
And that's pretty good where I come from.
Huh. Where do you come from?
Where else? South Bespin!
Your special blood
is going to make me invincible.
Those are my reasons.
[whimpers]
Yes. Accept your fate.
It is your destiny.
- [whimpering]
- You don't have to overdo it.
[grunting]
Why are you--
[beeping]
[screams, grunts]
[groans]
[Migs] It was on.
Mando battled his way onto the ship
with the help of Bo-Katan.
- It was awesome.
- [both grunting]
I got you now.
- [laughs wickedly]
- [grunts]
[yells]
[Mando] Come on.
- [guns cocking]
- [elevator dings]
- [swishing]
- [gunfire]
[R2-D2 beeping]
[Migs] The battle ended with the arrival
of the most famous Jedi of them all.
It looks like you were expecting us
to know who you are.
I'm Luke Skywalker.
My father was Darth Vader?
Oh, come on! I'm kind of a big deal!
[Mando] Mm. If you say so.
[sighs] I was beckoned by the call
of a young one named Grogu.
- Where is he?
- At your feet.
[speaking indistinctly]
You're not very big.
- [groans]
- Ugh!
Right, right. Size matters not.
He needs to be trained. By a Jedi.
I know.
Can I have a moment with him?
Kid.
I guess this is goodbye.
I have to let you see
my face this one time.
Goodbye, Grogu.
I hope I see you again,
maybe in a whole other series of events.
[Migs] And so the kid left with that
Luke guy
and his little beepee-boopy friend.
Grogu had finally found his family,
but Mando had lost his.
[all sobbing]
Don't worry, it all worked out.
He's here, isn't he?
[all cheering]
We tracked that thieving Migs
and the ship he stole from us
to the Mos Eisley Cantina
on Tatooine.
But get this, he's at a party
with The Mandalorian
and that little green kid!
Our archenemies!
Well, The Mandalorian
may have wiped us out of Nevarro,
but today, we pirates will triumph!
[all cheering]
You go out and collect
every pirate in the sector,
and when you have them all together,
launch an attack on that cantina!
[laughs wickedly]
We shall leave our enemies reeling!
- [upbeat music playing]
- [indistinct chatter]
[squealing]
[whimpering]
Hey, take it easy
with the little guy.
Okay, that's it.
This party is a bit too off the hook.
- Ah, yeah!
- The kid and I should be heading home.
- [all groaning]
- You can't leave now.
All the guests haven't arrived.
You have so many friends who want
to see you.
That sounds exhausting.
You're gonna make me cry
and you know I don't cry.
- [Grogu whines]
- [groans]
You see this sad face? It can get sadder.
We really have to go.
[somber instrumental music playing]
Okay, fine! We'll stay.
[all cheering]
The story continues.
Oh! Oh! Mando, tell us what happened
after Grogu left with Luke Skywalker.
And what did Boba Fett do
after he fought the Imperials with you?
That's his story,
and he's not here to tell it.
Even if he was, Boba Fett is not one
to trumpet his own accomplishments.
[trumpets playing]
Felicitations upon this festive gathering!
presenting the most excellent
Daimyo of Tatooine,
the sort of son of Jango Fett.
Boba Fett!
And his guests Fennec Shand
and Krrsantan!
[trumpets]
Just ignore me. I'm not here.
A little over the top, don't you think?
When you spend months
eating dirt in the desert
you can tell me how to live
when things start to go good.
[gasps] You're Boba Fett,
the greatest bounty hunter of them all.
He's okay.
[stutters] Tell us how you got to be
Daimyo on Tatooine.
No, no. I want to know how Mando
got Grogu back.
Well, I want to hear about Boba Fett.
Good sirs!
The two stories you wish to hear
are serendipitously intertwined,
and both end with the victory
of the heroic Boba Fett.
Gather round and I shall delight you
with this glorious tale.
It's a whole actual book?
Not a big reader, huh?
I have to get up early in the morning,
skip a few chapters.
- I live to serve.
- [Grogu coos]
Boba Fett and Fennec Shand
returned to Tatooine,
where Boba Fett took care
of some unfinished business
at the domicile of his former employer.
[speaking Huttese] Die wonna wonga.
[guns cocking]
No wanna wonga!
[majordomo in English] While Boba Fett
settled into his new Daimyo-citude,
The Mandalorian
was on a quest of his own.
Sadly, the razor crest was no more.
So he visited Peli Motto
to acquire a new vehicle.
I want to go see the kid,
just to make sure he's safe.
Oh, you're so cute.
Admit it. You love the little guy
and you miss him. We won't tease you.
Fine! Yes, I... I miss him.
[all giggling]
When I see Grogu,
I'm going to give him this.
Very, very funny. That's funny.
What's the real gift?
That's it. It's a suit of chain mail
made from Beskar steel.
Right. Right, right.
You know, kids hate clothes.
They want a nice speeder bike or something
with tassels on the handlebars.
Something like that.
You know, something that moves.
Beskar is sacred to all Mandalorians!
Ugh, fine! You do you.
I'll help you go see the kid.
I got a new ship for you.
I hope you're wearing socks
because they're about to get knocked off!
Ta-da! Isn't it great?
Uh...
Only used once
by a 10-year-old on Boonta Eve.
Nice kid. Really hated sand.
No.
Right, right, right, right, right.
Not for you, not for you.
I got it, I got it, I got it, I got it.
How about this?
Hard pass.
Picky, picky, picky.
There's plenty more to choose from.
Nope. Uh-huh.
Wow. No!
- [beeping]
- [Mando] No way! Never.
You are a tough customer.
All right. I was saving this
last one for you. Russell!
Hit it.
It's a Naboo N-1 Starfighter.
This beauty was used
by the Royal Security Force
during the Clone Wars,
and it's got the battle scars to prove it.
And because you hate droids
and I like you,
I've replaced the Astromech slot
with a seat for that
special little green-eared
someone in your life.
Total retail price?
You couldn't afford it.
My asking price?
Give that kid a big hug for me.
Sold.
- [keys jingling]
- [whistles]
So The Mandalorian flew off to pay
a visit to his diminutive green ward.
This proved to be a case
of easier said than done.
Grogu, it's me!
- Daddy!
- No!
You cannot see him.
He is my responsibility.
- [grunts]
- [electricity crackling]
[beeping]
Okay! Take it easy, big guy.
I know you miss Grogu, and I sympathize,
but he is with Master Luke.
We can't let Grogu's attachment
to you disrupt his training.
Use the Force, Grogu.
Pick up a rock.
- Good.
- Ah! [chuckles]
Very good!
Stupid good.
Wow. You're force building
at a high school level.
[laughs] Ooh!
- [coos]
- [grunts]
We'll try again after lunch. [grunts]
I don't want the kid to flunk.
Eventually, Grogu
will have to choose his own path.
- But for now...
- I'll go.
But can you give him this?
- [beeping]
- Yes, that's it.
- That's the gift.
- [beeping]
No, it's not a speeder bike.
- It's precious Beskar steel!
- [grunts]
No, he can't sell the steel
to buy a speeder bike.
So The Mandalorian returned
to Tatooine to assist Boba Fett,
who is encountering fierce resistance
to his rule
from the dreaded Pyke crime syndicate.
The Mandalorian was a warrior,
and now he was back in his element.
I, regrettably, was not in my element.
While Mando, Fennec and their allies
waged a valiant fight, Boba Fett...
ran away.
I went to get help! Tell it right!
Yes, great and merciful one.
Boba Fett heroically ran away to get help.
Meanwhile, Luke Skywalker presented Grogu
with the gift
The Mandalorian left behind.
[speaking indistinctly]
The Force is strong with Grogu
but he cannot be distracted like this.
He has to choose between his training
with me
and reuniting with The Mandalorian.
I think he's already made his choice.
[laughing]
Yes. Yes, it's very you.
Oh! [giggles]
[sighs] I sure hope my next student
won't be this difficult.
[dramatic music playing]
[grunts]
Things were looking bad
for The Mandalorian
but then Boba Fett made
his triumphant, heroic return,
because he didn't really run away.
He was always there.
Now you're overdoing it.
[dramatic music playing]
Finally! A monster I can like!
[yelps] I take that back!
[grunting]
Mando, stop playing with that rancor!
[straining] It's playing with me!
Good thing I brought somebody with me.
[giggles]
Kid! [grunting]
- Am I happy... to see... you.
- [thudding]
Use the Force!
Knock this monster into the next galaxy.
[growling]
- [Grogu grunts]
- [Mando sighs]
Putting it to sleep works, too.
And so, with the help of the returning
Din Djarin,
the great Daimyo Boba Fett
defeated the Pykes
and brought peace to Mos Espa.
For all of our firepower, in the end,
it was the little one who saved us.
What? What about me?
I brought him there from the spaceport.
I was his ride!
Yes, congratulations.
Things looked good for Mando and Grogu
but there was danger ahead.
For unbeknownst to them,
Moff Gideon had escaped
New Republic custody
- and was closing--
- [all exclaiming]
- [thudding]
- [all screaming]
[yelling]
- Hello, Mando.
- [guns cocking]
Happy birthday to us.
It's not my birthday,
it's just a party!
[Mando] Pirates.
We won't be able
to hold them off on our own.
I shall engage them diplomatically
and negotiate an amicable settlement.
[lasers firing]
Not so amicable. [whimpers]
Nobody panic.
Bo-Katan and her fellow Mandalorians
will be here soon,
and they will help us. I know it.
How can you be so sure?
Because we defeated Moff Gideon together.
Because we are heirs to a legacy
of commitment and devotion
going back to the ancient
ancestors of Mandalore.
And also because she's
sitting right over there.
[grunts]
No way I'd ever miss your party.
Thanks for the invite, Peli.
- [thudding]
- [all exclaiming]
No more inspirational speeches, Mando.
Give up.
You'll have to come through all of us.
But these guys first.
Got to adjust the hair for the helmet.
- [all grunting]
- [guns firing]
No! No, no, no.
[exclaiming]
[all exclaiming]
[screaming]
Gonna need some help here.
[all cheering]
Wow! Boba Fett, you're the best.
Hey, what are we? Bantha Poodoo?
Welcome to my world.
We're not safe yet.
Those pirates will be back
with plenty of reinforcements.
We're going to be all right.
Just like in our final victory
over Moff Gideon on Mandalore.
What did you do there?
It's a good story. I will tell you.
Does everybody have to tell a story?
Yes! It's very inspiring.
[sighs wearily] I'm sure it is.
Go right ahead.
Din Djarin had finally
reunited with Grogu.
Now he needed to redeem himself
and reclaim his status as a Mandalorian.
So he and Grogu journeyed to be
with the armorer and her covert.
Din Djarin, you have proven
your valor in many battles,
saved the Mandalorians from great harm,
- and defeated five separate monsters.
- [beeps]
Here is your free sandwich.
So does this mean you won't punish me
for taking off my helmet
when I said goodbye to Grogu?
You still must be cast out as an apostate!
I knew you'd understand.
But the lore says I can be redeemed
if I bathe in the living waters
of Mandalore.
That will never happen.
- And?
- It did happen!
Oh, I'm glad I'm wearing a helmet,
because my face is bright red under here.
It's all right.
We're in this together now.
Yes, all the Mandalorians
were now joined in a common cause.
And just in time.
Now that I have escaped
from my New Republic captors,
I will destroy the Mandalorians
once and for all.
In a battle suit
made of pure Beskar steel.
Yes.
All of the galaxy will fear me!
Wrong color!
This is for my beach party armor!
[Bo-Katan] Aware of Moff Gideon's threat,
Mando and Grogu returned to Nevarro,
where Greef Karga had a surprise in store!
With Moff Gideon on the loose,
I worry about you and the kid,
so I have a gift for Grogu.
[all cheering]
The Anzellans
made you a new protector
who's actually your old protector.
Behold!
This is IG-12.
How are you?
He cannot speak
unless Grogu is at the controls.
Wait! Grogu can operate him
from his chest?
Yes, yes.
Grogu, are you speaking through IG-12 now?
Yes yes.
Are you kidding me?
No, no.
This is gonna annoy me, right?
Probably, probably
With Grogu even more powerful now,
and the tribes of Mandalore
forged into one united clan,
our combined forces launched an attack
on Moff Gideon's base.
The Imperials will feel my tongs!
I'm going to give them
such a pinch! For Mandalore!
Oh! The dark saber is pretty good, too.
[all screaming]
- [dramatic music playing]
- [both grunting]
[all yelling]
[Bo-Katan] Just when it looked like
it was lights out for Mando,
he was rescued
[squealing] by Grogu!
No, no, no.
[IG-12] Uh-oh! Uh-oh! Uh--
[grunts]
[yells]
[Moff] Bo-Katan and Din Djarin!
Your story ends now.
Does it smell like yellow paint in here?
No, it does not!
[all grunting]
[grunting continues]
[Moff cackles]
[grunting]
[grunts]
Nothing can stop me now!
Except a giant flaming ship
crashing into the planet.
Very well. I'll be destroyed,
but I'll take you with me.
Nothing can save you from...
Oh, right, the Force.
[Bo-Katan] At last, Mandalore was returned
to the Mandalorians.
Din Djarin adopted Grogu and vowed
to train him.
You are now Din Grogu!
[roars]
And peace was restored
for a tiny bit.
Whoa, whoa. What does that mean?
What happened next?
I can tell that one,
and it is quite a story.
Drop your popcorn. The pirates are back!
[wicked laughter]
Avast, Mandalorian!
Today you will see your end.
Gorian Shard?
I thought you were destroyed.
I am his nephew, Dorian Shard!
Totally different guy.
So what, are you, like,
a big plant or something?
[groans] I am not a plant!
I am plant-like, and you will pay
for what you did to my uncle.
Fire!
[Peli] Aah!
[laughing maniacally]
- [both grunting]
- Fall back!
Get back inside!
- [panting]
- Aah! Poodoo!
Okay, that's it.
We're done.
We can't beat Fern Boy out there.
Got any more of those
self-destruct thingies?
No self-destructing.
Well, what else are we gonna do?
We're all alone here!
No, I was alone.
But not anymore.
Now I have Grogu, and I have all of you.
We are strong because we are a family,
and because Grogu can move stuff
by just waving at it.
Peli, you still have
those junkers in your yard?
Do tauntaun smell bad on the outside?
I have no idea.
Trust me, they do. Whoo-hoo! P-ew!
IG-11, cover us.
I will comply.
Pirates, you will fail,
because I am an assassin droid,
like the three or four other
versions of myself before me.
[all yelling]
He's a dancing machine.
Here you go.
My empire of junk.
It's beautiful.
Kid, do your thing.
I am out of ammunition.
Friends, you may come out
and support me now.
I believe I have been pranked.
[Mando] No, you haven't.
Dorian Shard, go now before we uproot you!
[laughs] Yeah!
- You better leave!
- Put the petal to the metal! [laughs]
Oh, for the last time, I am not a plant!
I have feet!
Attack!
[screeches]
[exclaiming]
[grunts]
[shudders]
First mate,
we are outnumbered on the ground.
Prepare the heavy cannon
for orbital bombardment.
[roars]
[creaking]
Oh, whoa!
[grunts]
[yelps, grunts]
[yells]
Hey pal, have a mynock on me!
- Whoo!
- [screaming]
Why didn't I get those hatches greased
when I had the chance?
I need firepower!
[exclaims] A 50-year-old baby!
[laughs wickedly]
Hey, you got your speeder bike!
[coos]
Pirate flagship, open fire!
- [squeals]
- Huh?
My ship!
All my stuff was on there.
[groans]
Got anything to say now, Dorian?
Eh! You wouldn't hurt
an innocent houseplant, would you?
See? [grunts]
Hey, look, he's soiling himself!
[exclaiming]
Mando, you did it!
No, we did it because I was able
to put down my armor, figuratively,
and let all of you into my life.
So... I guess I did do it.
That's what I meant, you dum-dum.
And though this wasn't
the assignment I was expecting,
I'm glad you put on a fake mustache
and tricked us into coming here.
Does that mean...
Yes, I am ready to enjoy
the party with my friends.
Hit it!
[upbeat music playing]
[camera shutter clicking]